TARIQ ABUSHEIKH SOFTWARE ENGINEER



★ tariq.abusheikh@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/tarigabusheikh



tariq86.github.io

SUMMARY

Ambitious full-stack software engineer with years of experience in software development and project management. Experienced in identifying new product needs and deploying optimal solutions. Specialized in managing development teams implementing internal processes to guarantee code quality and ensure development speed.

SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Frontend: JS, HTML5, CSS3, React, Vue, NPM Backend: Node/ES6, PHP (Composer, Laravel, Yii), Python (Django, Flask), REST, GraphQL (Prisma), Linux, Docker, HTTP, SSL, Apache, Nginx, AWS (EC2, RDS, Route53, VPC)

Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, Redis, SQLite App Development: Flutter, Java, React Native,

Swift, Apollo, Expo, Redux

DevOps: CI/CD, git, svn, unit testing

Programming Methodologies: OOP, MVC,

TDD, BDD, Functional programming Professional Skills: R&D (research,

prototyping, MVP), product & project Management, agile, SCRUM, team leadership,

management, mentorship, training

EDUCATION

B.S., Bioinformatics @ St. Edward's University August 2005 - August 2009

Presidential Scholar

WORK EXPERIENCE

Adjunct Instructor @ UT Austin Code Camp

July 2020 - Present

- Teaching intensive full-stack web development using MERN stack
- Consistently rated over 4/5 on all instructor metrics

Director of Web Development @ NetworkIP

May 2011 - October 2020

- Oversaw development and maintenance of three white-label SaaS products and multiple APIs for B2B telecom company
- Hired and managed 5 developers, conducting interviews, providing feedback in 1:1 code reviews, and mentoring
- Consulted new clients alongside solutions and business development teams to plan optimal product integration based on customer's goals, and translated desired setup into development tasks
- Led migration from legacy infrastructure to new AWS-powered backend
- Reduced bug reports by over 75% by:
 - Implementing unit testing to improve code quality and reduce bugs
 - Enforcing code style, ensuring code readability and maintainability
 - Migrating from SVN to Git and implementing new branching workflow, virtually eliminating merge conflicts
 - Standardizing all tools used by development teams to remove working environment inconsistencies
 - Setting up CI/CD pipeline to automate testing and code deployment
 - Organizing weekly SCRUMs for developers to share progress updates and receive feedback
 - Documenting all processes and tools on wiki pages for developer reference and easier on-boarding